[Music]
hi and welcome to this session on what's
new in business
Central pobi embedded reports and pobi
Reporting my name is Brian Nelson I'm a
program manager in the business Central
team in this
release uh in the next minor uh first
you will see that we have new powerbi
reports enabling uh reporting on your
business Central data in
powerbi with powerbi you will of course
when you install apps you get apps in
powerbi but we also embedded those
reports in within business Central so
that you can access them directly from
within business Central it requires a
bit of setup or
configuration very little and there's
learning content docs content describing
how you set up of course but also each
of the 76 reports that are in there in
total describing what the report is
about and how you would usually navigate
filter and and use the
reports and later on in one of the next
miners uh we will provide more demo data
so it's easier to demonstrate all the
capabilities that powerbi is offering
let's take a closer look before we look
at the
product the powerbi uh apps once you
have installed them will be embedded
uh within business Central meaning that
you can access them uh through role
centers or actions in the uh um role
Explorer and get a one page per report
uh from the app later on you'll be able
to select specific
visuals enrio and Blas has a separate um
session on the powerbi embed that you
can also watch if you want to do your
own embedding from powerbi
there's
um a a piece of uh setup that you need
to do you need to pick the right uh apps
for the right set of reports uh and you
do that from within BC for the finance
report there is some setup for account
category so you get all of your
financial kpis right but it's it's
straightforward and there's even a
wizard to take you through it uh the
first time you do
it um here we have the account
categories that you need for your
financial kpis there are some defaults
but if you're running your own chart of
accounts or if you have even added your
own account categories you might want to
modify
this you can access the new po reports
through the role centers where we have
added them to like we have added the
relevant report for the relevant role
centers um if you need to find specific
ones or the first time where you just
want to to browse through all of it you
can access all
76 reports through the role
Explorer either by searching powerbi or
for the specific report when you open a
report and hit the question mark to get
help you will see that there is a mini
help in the help pane it will give you a
brief explanation of what the report is
about and then in the release when we
release we will take you through a
separate page for each of the rep report
describing what the report is about what
data is behind it and what you can do
with the filtering and what is supposed
to show you uh with your data and then
of course uh related or additional
resources we will uh link you to the new
uh analytics content that we have
provided in
docs but let's take a look at how this
looks like uh in business
Central so here I have business Central
and uh I want to take a look at the new
powerbi
reports I can go
to uh the role Explorer I can try and
search for
powerbi it will give me all the results
and I can start scrolling
down and pick one of
them um it's a good place to start if
you just want to browse through the
different uh reports let's take the
balance sheet it is one of the reports
in the finance app and it's embedded
here in BC connected to my data we'll
get to the connection in a few seconds
you can see I started my year in July it
ends in June it has it all I can click
on this one or right click it and say uh
show next level which will expand the
balance sheet and and uh show me more
data if I need to dig into uh one of the
items like finish good Goods for
September I can right click it and drill
through and in this case I would pick
the balance sheet uh drill through
because it comes from the balance sheet
and I have my data here actually this
balance sheet drill through
um table is in a separate report you can
also access it uh directly if you want
or if you need
to and of course you have some filtering
if you need to do some filtering to
either troubleshoot validate data or any
other thing
let's go back to to this one so I have
my balance sheet here I found the report
in the role Explorer uh if I really want
to use it every day I probably want to
bookmark it and then I will have it in
my Ru Center where I can use
personalization to move it around in my
navigation or it might na pain let's
close this
one okay and you can see that I put in
the financial overview which is a
different report showing me
kpis uh I can also in these reports in
most of them I can uh either um expand
it a bit or there are some of the
reports where if it's meaningful I can
drill through to the uh underlying
data there are uh some filters that I
can
apply uh in this year when I'm looking
at a financial overview I probably want
to only look at the current year I'll
scroll a bit down
24 and then I will just see my data for
the current year and of course it's
powerbi it will remember my uh
setting and let's take another look at
one of the U sales
overview the sales overview will give
you uh kpis for for sales um some more
details in some of them and again you
have filtering over here so let's look
at the setup that you will go through in
order to set up these reports and we
will uh either notify you um or uh if
you see the blog post we will take you
through uh to uh pobi appsource where
you will install the apps just like any
other apps in
appsource in powerbi when you install
apps they will just um the first uh
thing you will be asked about is where
in what workspace do you want to install
it you can either add them to an
existing workspace if you want want to
or you can create a new one like I have
done here business Central and then uh I
will put all my apps in here currently
the apps are per
company uh so if I want to run powerbi
on multiple um business Central
companies I can either create a separate
workspace for each of the companies or I
could duplicate um or reinstall the app
like I need to install the app once for
each company that I have in the current
implementation so I have my apps here
they're in a business Central
workspace so in business Central the
first time you select um a powerbi
report or if you actually go to the
powerbi chart in
um in the role Center where we have
powerbi chart you will be um uh prompted
with a wizard that takes you through the
setup in this case we just say yes we
want to go through it the first thing
you will have to select is how or what
calendar do you want to use then the
regular calendar calendar or your fiscal
calendar that is based off of your
accounting periods or a weekly calendar
maybe if you're on retailer or other and
I just need to select
it um I can select uh weekdays I can
select um time zone and I can select we
have defaulted to three years of data
like for comparison year over-ear and
maybe having some historical data for
the uh the time series charts and
Analysis but you can you can modify it
if you want
to you can also select the holidays uh
if you have any uh reports that where
that is
relevant and the last page uh we asked
you for uh input is and I filled it in
because I've been there already but if
you're starting from from a new company
this would be blank and you would for
each one of them each of the seven apps
you would pick the workspace where you
have put the app selected and then you
would pick the relevant
app and
then um the pages will refer to the the
reports uh in that
app and the same you could go through
invoice uh sorry inventory has uh two
different app that it needs if you want
them you don't have to fill in all of
them at once you can just start with
Finance or you can start with sale just
to see how it goes if you want to and of
course you can it's a assisted setup um
or wizard so you can run it uh after
you've you've closed it and maybe add
more apps as you
go um the wizard will pick up your
environment some demo environment I have
here and the company
name and that will be inserted into the
semantic model in
pobi
um so that it knows where to fetch the
data if you need to uh and when you're
copying stuff around in in powerbi or if
if you're setting it up manually you can
actually go to the semantic model in
powerbi and then insert these
parameters but it's much easier to do it
through the connector so now I have set
up um my powerbi apps uh I can find them
in the RO
Explorer um hopefully the the default
will work for the financial
reports but if I need to I can go
into powerbi
connector and I can either go through
the connector because I can revisit my
setup there um I can pick the general uh
stuff and then I can pick the specific
for each of the the apps I can select
the apps and I can select some dates for
for the data that will be
retrieved for the finance report I need
to set up some account categories or I
need to do a prop mapping because as you
saw with the powerbi sorry the financial
overview uh report it produces some kpis
those kpis are based on uh categories of
your or categorization of your data and
in order to have have that correct you
need to set up a mapping so on the left
hand side this is what pobi uh uses to
calculate these uh different kpis quick
Rao cach
radio uh and so forth and you will just
um you can either pick the default or
you can go in let's say I remember I did
this liquid asset maybe you have a
category and you're just using
maybe you're just using the cash
category maybe you have multiple cash
categories or maybe you have something
that you would also consider liquid
asset that you want to go into uh the
kpis for that and you can just add it
here so so these two elements picking
the apps that you installed and setting
up the account categories
for uh the finance report is all you
need to do to set it up and then you're
ready to start using powerbi reporting
embedded in business Central
so once you get started with powerbi
reporting you probably won't be able to
stop but there will be more um in one of
the coming releases minor releases
hopefully the second one we will add
demo data so that um when you run on
your own business Central tenant or your
own environment you'll be able to spin
up a company add that demo data and then
start using the reports where you will
have a a rich set of financial data uh
project data fixed assets data and then
some of the other modules will will come
later so that you can start um
demonstrating exploring uh powerbi
reporting without having to connect to
your production environment so much
better uh demo data for powerbi
reporting we will extend the set of apps
we have the seven apps we have with an
app for subscription billing so that
will powerbi will be embedded as
reporting there too and we will also get
one for sustainability we'll get one for
fixed
assets uh and then more of the other
modules will come in later versions in
this release because we're still making
a few changes um to the uh apps we um we
keep it to ourselves but from the next
release which means uh release 26 which
is April
uh we will open source the report files
like the the powerbi X PBX uh files that
you will be able to access from GitHub
that means that you can take the file
and put a different color on it add more
uh data if you want and if you have
access to more data you can combine it
with other sources you can create your
own
reports uh and you can completely uh
rearrange it the way you want but you
will have a starting point uh for each
of these apps which maybe bring you uh
fast forward to to to have your own
powerbi reporting so with that go and
explore in the next minor release when
it's out there and thank you for
watching this session